我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成為另一個存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
她是我女兒  海倫娜
This is my daughter, Helena.
她父親殺了她的未婚夫的時候
When her father killed her fiance,
她就已經變得既黑暗又扭曲了
she changed into something dark and twisted.
我爸爸不配得到第二次機會
My father doesn't deserve a second chance--
新的人生
a second life.
這是學會控制你的力量
This is about learning to control your strength.
奧利  結束了  我們得離開這艘船
Ollie, it's over! We got to get off this ship!
雨果•曼海姆
Hugo Mannheim.
因為詐騙  勒索  謀殺被通緝
Warrants out for racketeering, extortion, murder--
黑手黨重要人物
The goombah trifecta.
但他從來不單獨行動  所以自己小心點
But he never travels alone, so watch your back,
也照顧好自己的同伴
watch your partner's back.
出發吧
Let's go.
謝謝你今晚幫我照看我爸
Thanks for helping me keep watch over my dad tonight.
只要斯萊德還逍遙法外  我們兩家就都不安全
As long as Slade's out there, neither of our families are safe.
星城警局  把武器放在地上
This is the SCPD! Put your weapons on the ground!
快快快
Move, move, move!
不許動
Freeze!
走
Go.
快走
Go!
弗蘭克•波提納爾
Frank Bertinelli.
我女兒派你來殺我嗎
My daughter sent you to kill me.
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第十七集
爸爸  你沒事吧  受傷了嗎
Dad, are you all right? Are you hurt?
我沒事  親愛的
Yeah, I'm fine, sweetheart.
我知道你不信
Listen, I know you don't exactly believe
對嫌疑犯讀米蘭達法則這一套
in reading perps their Mirandas,
但你不能直接把人扔出窗外
but you can't just toss a guy out of a window.
他打傷了你
He shot you.
我這不沒事嗎
And I'm still here, ain't I?
下次自己克制一點
Just next time, show a little restraint.
我那樣就很克制了
That was me showing restraint.
警探  我們有另一個問題
Detective. We have another problem.
我知道  弗蘭克•波提納爾被拘留
Yeah, I know. With Frank Bertinelli in custody,
女老大回市裡就只是時間問題
it's just a matter of time before she-ro is back in town.
她是誰
Who is she?
海倫娜•波提納爾
Helena Bertinelli.
黑手黨老大弗蘭克•波提納爾的女兒
Daughter of mafia boss Frank Bertinelli.
我喜歡稱呼她為  奧利弗的神經前女友
Or as I like to call her, Oliver's psycho ex-girlfriend
執意報復她的父親
hell-bent on revenge against her father.
前女友
Ex-girlfriend?
你就聽到這個詞了嗎
That's what you took from that sentence?
等等  她為什麼這麼想殺她爸爸
Wait, why does she want her father killed so badly?
他派人殺了她的未婚夫
He had her fiance murdered.
-她想報復  -讓我想到了
- She wants payback. - Puts the many fights
我和我爸爸吵過的架
I've had with my father in perspective.
過去一年裡  我一直在監視海倫娜
I've been keeping tabs on Helena over the past year.
最後一次出現是一個月之前
Last known sighting was a month ago,
在巴勒莫[義大利城市]
Palermo.
她很忙啊
She's been busy.
如果你說的"忙"
If by "Busy,"
是指酷刑折磨和殺害那些
you mean torturing and killing mafiosos
可能知道她父親下落的黑手黨成員
that might know where her father is.
逮捕波提納爾一事上了新聞
Bertinelli's arrest just hit the wires.
在海倫娜訂機票趕回來之前
How long do you think we
你覺得我們還有多少時間
have before Helena books a ticket back home?
來吧
Go ahead.
斯萊德  拜託
Slade, please--
為什麼還不走
Why aren't we moving yet?
我們想辦法修復了船體
We managed to repair the hull.
但是引擎損傷太嚴重了
But the engine is too damaged.
-那就修好它  -我做不到
- So fix it. - I can't.
我不知道怎麼修
I don't know how!
那就去找會修的
Then find somebody who does.
大家好  我是勞蕾爾  是個酒癮者
Hi, my name's Laurel, I'm an alcoholic.
你好  勞蕾爾
Hi, Laurel.
今天實際上是我第二次參加會議
And this is actually my second meeting today.
這個...
It's just, uh...
這個真的太難了  因為我不知道
It's just so hard, because I don't know
一整天該做什麼好
what to do with myself all day.
我是個律師
I'm a lawyer,
我曾是律師
well, I... was...a lawyer.
我很喜歡這份工作
I loved it.
但我想我更喜歡喝酒
But I guess I loved drinking more.
我知道我和你們一起在這裡時  我能做到
I know that I can make it down here with all of you.
但是我不知道在外面能不能做到
I just...I'm not sure I can make it out there.
總之
Anyway.
謝謝大家讓我分享
Thank you for letting me share.
唐納  來電
星城法院
謝謝你過來
Thanks for coming.
抱歉是那樣的結局
Sorry about the way things ended here.
不用道歉
No, don't be.
你幫了我  亞當
You did me a favor, Adam.
那是我降到低谷的唯一方法
It was the only way I was going to hit bottom,
而且
and...
而且我做到了
and I did.
不如你現在幫我個忙吧
How about you do me a favor now...
回來工作
Come back to work.
你想要我回來嗎
You want me back?
我在找人處理這起剛到的案子
I'm looking for someone to try this case that just came in,
老實說  我第一個想到的就是你
and honestly, yours was the first name that came to mind.
酒吧還要對我提出制裁呢
I'm still facing sanctions from the bar.
我在紀律委員會有個朋友
Oh, I got a buddy on the disciplinary committee.
我幫你擺平這件事了
I squared things for you.
昨晚星城警局進行突襲  逮捕了弗蘭克•波提納
An SCPD raid last night brought in Frank Bertinelli.
他回星城來收債
He came back to Starling to collect on some old debts.
地檢辦很明確地
Now, the DA's office is clear
要控告他  你來控告他
to prosecute him; for you to prosecute him.
謝謝你的提議  亞當  但為什麼是我
I appreciate the offer, Adam, but why me?
你在創新聯合會時勝訴的
Well, there are rico counts
反詐騙腐敗組織集團犯罪案件數
that your time at CNRI
讓你有資格勝任
make you ideally suited for.
勞蕾爾  這是一起案子
Laurel, it's a case.
如果你想要  它就是你的
If you want it, it's yours.
但前提是你得準備好
But only if you're ready.
威登酒吧
今天是什麼日子
What's the special occasion?
我領工資了  所以
I got paid. So, you know,
如果你覺得還不夠好
if you don't think it's nice enough,
你只能怪自己
you only have yourself to blame
不給我漲工資了
for not giving me that raise.
羅伊  我很喜歡
Roy, I love it.
謝謝你
Thank you.
等  等我一下
Hey, give me-- give me a second,
我忘記訂貨了
I forgot to put an order in.
好的
OK.
有新進展嗎
Hey, what's going on?
我找到海倫娜的未婚夫邁克爾•斯塔頓了
I got a line on Michael Statton, Helena's fiancé.
費利西蒂  他死了五年了
Felicity, he's been dead for five years.
所以他昨晚租了
Which makes the fact that
一輛車這件事尤其令人印象深刻
he rented a car last night very impressive.
那是海倫娜
That's Helena.
有車載衛星定位系統  我黑進去了
The car's got GPS, I hacked into it.
好吧  她在往星城開
Yeah. She's heading straight for Starling City.
你準備好出外勤了嗎
You ready to get back in the field?
我以為你永遠都不會問呢
I thought you'd never ask.
一切都結束了 海倫娜
It's over, Helena.
從車裡出來
Get out of the car!
槍
Gun!
別殺我
Don't hurt me!
退後
Stand down.
Stand...down!
-別殺我  -閃電
- Don't hurt me! - Speedy!
夠了
Enough!
他只是海倫娜佈置的誘餌
He's just Helena's decoy.
她在哪裡
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know!
有個小妞給我錢讓我開這輛車兜風
Some chick just paid me to take the car for a joy ride.
我發誓
I swear!
求你們不要殺我
Please don't kill me.
我下個月就要結婚了
I'm getting married next month.
開你的車
Just drive.
據星城警局的線索  載海倫娜進城的人
According to the SCPD, the guy that gave Helena
是一名在星城大學
a ride into town is
專攻政治社會學的22歲學生
a 22-year-old poly sci major at SCU,
他還加入了一個兄弟會
and a member of gamma tau,
這就能解釋
which totally explains the whole
我不知道在幫助並教唆一名重犯的戲碼了
"I didn't know I was aiding and abetting a known felon" thing.
只要是女的就能讓兄弟會的人做任何事
Anyone with boobs can get a frat boy to do anything.
-我曾經是兄弟會成員  -我不說了
- I was a frat boy. - I rest my case.
至少她沒殺他  還不錯
At least she didn't kill him. That's something.
這麼克制不是海倫娜的風格
It's not like Helena to show restraint.
聽上去你好像很瞭解她啊
It sounds like you have a type.
繼續注意員警的動向
Keep tabs on the police.
如果警方有她的線索  馬上通知我
Let me know if they get any leads on her.
我去找幾個線人問問
I'll do some canvassing.
-你還好嗎  -還好
- You OK? - Yeah.
明天這個時候  就會像什麼都沒發生過了
By this time tomorrow, it'll be like nothing happened.
那是米拉庫魯的優點之一
That's one upside to Mirakuru.
唯一的優點
The only one.
我知道你打算說什麼
Look, I know what you're going to say.
我昨晚已經控制得很好了
I had it under control last night.
是啊  好到我差點就又射你一箭了
Yeah, so under control that I almost put another arrow in you.
我已經打算後退了  但你不給我機會
I was going to back off, but you never gave me a chance.
唯一讓你迅速清醒的事
The only thing that snapped you out of it
就是我提起西婭
was when I brought up Thea.
那就是你沖我喊我閃電的原因
That's why you called me Speedy.
我  我以為你想給我起個昵稱
I--I thought you were trying to give me a nickname.
但我要聲明  別叫我閃電
But for the record, don't call me Speedy.
記住了
Noted.
羅伊  你是個危險的人
Roy, you're dangerous.
我以為我是在幫你控制它
I thought I was helping you control it.
你是的  我是說
You are. I mean,
我看到一碗水就忍不住去拍它
I can't look at a bowl of water without slapping it.
數周以來你第一次出外勤
The first time that you're out in the field in weeks,
你就  準備好殺人了嗎
and...you're ready to kill somebody?
這可不行
Come on.
對不起  我幾個月前就應該讓你這麼做的
I'm sorry, I should have asked you to do this months ago.
做什麼
Asked me to do what?
遠離西婭
Stay away from Thea.
不  我  我做不到
No, I--I can't.
她在你身邊的時候非常不安全
She's not safe when she's around you.
你生氣失控時
I'm not sure anybody is
誰在你身邊都不安全
when you lose yourself to this rage.
你愛她
You love her.
所以你要按我說的做
And that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
太驚人了
Such a big uh-oh.
海倫娜
Helena?
是勞蕾爾
Laurel.
檢察官亞當•唐納宣佈
ADA Adam Donner announced
在短暫的休假之後勞蕾爾•蘭斯
the return of Laurel Lance to the D.A.'s office
正式回歸地方檢察官辦公室
after a brief sabbatical.
重大新聞
她將主導對波提納爾的起訴
She will lead the prosecution of Mr. Bertinelli.
陪審團的選定從今天開始
Jury selection starts today.
你來這裡做什麼
What are you doing here?
我從新聞上得知你拿到了幾個大案子
I heard you picked up some big new case on the news.
你怎麼不給我打電話
How come you didn't call me?
我想打的  但一切都發生的太快了
I was going to, but it all happened so fast.
再說  我覺得你和爸爸不會讓我
Plus, I thought you and dad would try and talk me out of
這麼快就重新開始工作
going back to work so soon.
你就是為這個來的
Which is why you're here.
我很擔心你
I'm just worried about you.
如果你擔心我會犯錯誤
If you're worried I'm going to slip,
我每天依然要參加兩場會議  而且
I'm still going to two meetings a day, and--
勞蕾爾  不是指那個
Laurel, it's not that.
所有人都知道波提納爾是個什麼貨色
Everybody knows what kind of guy Bertinelli is.
更不用說他那個已經準備回星城來
And not to mention his completely psychotic daughter,
殺掉他的精神病女兒
who's already on her way back to Starling City to kill him.
你怎麼知道的
How do you know that?
我不知道
I don't.
我只是希望你安全
I just want you to be safe.
我愛你的體貼
And I love you for caring.
但是莎拉  你從來沒見過我當律師
But Sara, you've never seen me be a lawyer before.
我真的很擅長這份工作
And I am really good at it.
我也很懷念
And I miss it.
我得走了
I have to run.
庭審可不能遲到
I can't be late for court.
這裡真是比貨船好多了啊
Yeah, this is much better than the freighter.
亨德里克  你喜歡在船上的話可以遊回去
You prefer boat, Hendrik, feel free to swim back.
莎拉說奧利弗在這活了一年多
Sara said Oliver survived here for over a year.
我們也可以的
We can do the same.
除非艾沃和他的手下找到我們
Unless Ivo and his men come find us.
我們不知道船上發生了什麼
We don't know what happened on the boat.
誰還活著  誰已經死了
Who's alive and who's dead.
莎拉  你在嗎
Sara, are you there?
斯萊德  奧利弗...
Slade! Is Oliver...
他很痛苦  是的
He's in pain, yes.
但他現在依然活著
But he's still breathing--for now.
斯萊德  聽著  你贏了  行了吧
Slade, listen, you won, OK?
亞馬遜號歸你了
You have the "Amazo."
放了奧利弗吧  你可以把我們留在這裡
Just let Oliver go, and then you can leave us here!
這就是我的問題  莎拉
Well, here's my problem, Sara.
我走不了
I can't leave.
-為什麼  -我們交火的時候
- Why not? - During our assault,
船的發動機損壞了
the ship's engine was damaged.
無法航行了
She won't sail.
很不幸交火時我還把工程師殺了
During the attack, unfortunately I decapitated the engineer.
所以怎麼處理我們的問題呢  莎拉
So what can we do about our problem, Sara?
你想要奧利弗回去
You want Oliver back,
而我需要一個有能力修船的人
and I need someone qualified to fix this boat.
為了奧利弗
For Oliver's sake,
我希望亨德里克先生跟你在一起
I sure hope a Mr. Hendrik is there with you.
非致命的箭
Non-lethal arrows?
玩這種小孩的玩意可不是你的風格
It's not like you to play with kid gloves.
羅伊怎麼樣了
How's Roy?
跟海倫娜一樣  他不太喜歡我作為導師的技巧
Like Helena, he is not too pleased with my skills as a mentor.
勞蕾爾不願放棄那案子
Laurel won't drop the case.
她現在就在去法庭的路上
She's headed to court right now.
-你要去哪兒  -去法庭
- Where are you going? - To the courthouse.
你忘帶你的小孩子箭頭了
Well, hey, you forgot your baby arrows.
我明白你那套不殺人的主張
Look, I get your whole no killing spree,
但如果最後要救勞蕾爾  殺掉海倫娜
but if it comes down to saving Laurel or killing Helena--
莎拉  並不只有這兩個選擇
Sara, those aren't the only two choices.
斯萊德威脅你的家人的時候
Well, you were happy enough to let Dig take the kill shot
你也高興地讓狄格下了殺手
when it was Slade threatening your family.
這不一樣
This is different.
我辜負了海倫娜
I failed Helena.
"女殺手"是我創造出來的
I created the "Huntress".
是啊  斯萊德也是你創造出來的
Yeah, well, you created Slade, too.
你說得對
You're right.
但一旦涉及我們的家人
But when it comes to our families...
我們倆頭腦就都不清楚
neither one of us thinks clearly.
所以你得留在這裡
Which is why you have to stay here.
奧利
Ollie.
我不能留下
I can't.
我不會讓勞蕾爾出任何事的
I'm not going to let anything happen to Laurel.
我也愛她
I love her, too.
你們覺得呢
What do you guys think?
我覺得如果"女殺手"出現
Oh, I think if the Huntress shows up,
你應該打爆她
you should totally kick her ass.
拜託別告訴我你也很擔心我
Please don't tell me you're worried about me, too.
不是  我只是想看看審判
No, I just wanted to watch the trial.
我聽說那個律師很特別
I heard the prosecutor was something special.
真奇怪
That's odd.
他們為什麼帶他從正門進來
Why are they bringing him in through the front entrance?
所有人都趴下
Everybody get down!
你好啊  爸爸
Hi, dad.
抱歉我來晚了  你可真不好找啊
Sorry I'm late, but you're a hard man to track down.
但你回到星城很合適
But it's fitting that you came back to Starling.
這是一切開始的地方
Where it all began.
是你殺了邁克爾的地方
Where you killed Michael.
我差一點就為你感到抱歉了
You know, I almost feel sorry for you.
海倫娜
Helena...
住手
Stop this.
奧利弗  你知道我不能
Oliver, you know I can't.
那你還在等什麼
Well, what are you waiting for?
我說  你還在等什麼
I said, what are you waiting for?!
海倫娜•波提納爾  把武器放下
Helena Bertinelli, put down your weapons
把手舉過頭頂
and place your hands above your head.
這麼說這是一個大陷阱...
So this was a big trap...
你就是誘餌
with you as the bait.
他們給你什麼好處
What did they offer you?
他們什麼好處也不用給我
Ah, they didn't have to offer me anything.
放棄吧  波提納爾女士  大樓被包圍了
Give up, Miss Bertinelli, the building's surrounded.
你一直都怎麼教導我的來著  爸爸
What was it you always taught me, daddy?
做好萬全的準備
Be prepared for anything.
動手
Now.
抓住人質  後退
Take hostages, and fall back.
別開槍  別開槍  他們手裡有人質
Hey, hold your fire, hold your fire! They have hostages!
別開槍  重復  別開槍  他們有人質
Hold fire. Say it again, hold fire. They've taken hostages.
勞蕾爾在哪兒  勞蕾爾在哪兒  她跟你一起嗎
Where's Laurel? Where's Laurel? Is she with you?
抱歉  蘭斯先生  我們走散了
I'm sorry, Mr. Lance, we got separated.
她還在裡面
She's still inside.
我們正在星城法院外進行直播
We are live outside the Starling City courthouse,
海倫娜•波提納爾和不明數量的攻擊者
where Helena Bertinelli and an unknown number of assailants
控制了整棟大樓
seized control of the entire building.
現在我被告知
And I'm now being told,
他們在裡面控制了一些人質
they are holding a number of hostages inside.
安排狙擊手帶著熱成像瞄準鏡
I want snipers with thermals on top
在兩個街區範圍內的所有大樓頂部待命
of every building for a two block radius.
不應該發生這種事的  上尉
This was not how it was supposed to go down, Captain!
你跟我保證說不會有傷亡的
You promised me there wouldn't be any casualties!
這是你的主意嗎  你這個混蛋
This was your idea, huh? You son of a bitch!
我女兒在裡面
Hey, my daughter's in there!
你們是怎麼想的
What were you guys thinking,
拿那麼多無辜的生命冒險
putting all those innocent lives at risk?
-聽著  我是在執行命令  -命令
- Listen! I was following orders. - Orders?!
波提納爾女士
Ms. Bertinelli.
任何人都不必死
No one has to die today.
我爸爸需要死
My father does.
除非你們把他交給我
And unless you hand him over to me,
不然我要開始殺人質了
I'm going to start killing hostages.
看吧  唐納先生
See this, Mr. Donner,
這就是你不管戴面具的瘋子的後果
is what happens when you let freaks with masks run wild.
把他們帶出去
Get them the hell out of here.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
是我媽打來的
It's my mom.
警探
Detective.
海倫娜•波提納爾控制了十名人質
Helena Bertinelli just took ten hostages.
勞蕾爾就是其中之一
Laurel's one of them.
我知道現在的情況
Yeah, I'm aware of the situation.
奧利弗  你在哪裡  你還好嗎
Oliver, where are you? Are you ok?
我以奧利弗的身份和蘭斯在一起
I'm with Lance as Oliver,
他剛剛打給綠箭俠了
and he just called the Arrow.
越來越難搞清
It's getting really hard to
誰知道誰的秘密身份了
keep track of who knows whose secret identity.
費利西蒂  勞蕾爾還在法院裡
Felicity, Laurel is still inside the courthouse.
你需要什麼  奧利弗
What do you need, Oliver?
-我的戰袍  -這就來
- My work clothes. - I'm on it.
讓莎拉接電話
Put Sara on the phone.
她不在這裡
She's not here.
她去哪了
Where is she?
你是好人嗎
Are you one of the good guys?
不  但我和好人是朋友
No, but I'm friends with them.
威登酒吧
-看著點  -去你的
- Dude, watch it. - Screw you!
西婭  我們分手吧
Thea, we need to break up.
什麼
What?!
不要
No.
不要是什麼意思
What do you mean, no?
西婭  我要和你分手
Thea, I'm breaking up with you.
不  不行
No, you're not.
你不能強迫我和你約會
You can't make me date you.
羅伊  昨天你才用全部積蓄
Roy, yesterday you gave me a bracelet
買了個手鐲送給我
worth every dime that you had,
現在卻要和我分手了
And now what, you want to end things?
你最近顯然不太好過
Look, you're clearly going through something right now,
我不會讓你一個人撐著的
and I'm not going to let you go through it alone.
我會永遠陪著你
I'm always going to be here for you.
不好意思  西婭  私人派對那個男的
Sorry, Thea. The guy from the private party
說我們上錯了伏特加  在發飆呢
said we stocked the wrong vodka, and he's freaking me out.
我們待會再談  好嗎
Look, we'll talk about this later, ok?
你受傷了嗎
Are you hurt?
我太笨了
I'm so stupid.
你不會想那麼做的
You don't want to do that.
相信我
Oh, no, trust me.
我需要
I do.
那你的戒酒的事怎麼辦
What about your sobriety?
你怎麼知道的
How do you know about that?
你鑰匙圈上的那個"A"
The "A" chip on your keychain.
30天
30 days.
戒酒30天
你知道我今天為什麼會來嗎
Do you even know why I'm here today?
原來我就是個裝飾
Turns out I'm decoration.
可有可無的裝飾
Expendable decoration.
你什麼意思
What do you mean?
整個庭審就是個幌子
This whole trial was a sham.
我早該想到的
I should have seen it.
莎拉是對的
Sara was right.
莎拉是
Sara, she's...
我妹妹
she's my sister.
她說我還沒有準備好
She said that I wasn't ready to come back, and...
我以為那是她保護過度
I just thought she was being overprotective.
姐妹之間總是這樣
Well, sisters can be like that.
你真該見見我的姐妹
You should meet mine.
她受了很多苦
She's gone through a lot.
她一定很堅強
She must have been so strong.
我只是
I just...
我想讓她和我自己看到
I wanted to show her, show myself...
我也依然很堅強
that I was still strong, too.
那展現給我看吧
So show me.
我們走
Let's go.
你在哪裡
Where are you?
在裡面  我找到勞蕾爾•蘭斯了
Inside. I've got Laurel Lance,
她沒事
she's ok.
是綠箭俠嗎
Is that the Arrow?
我在向南側的出口走
I'm headed to an egress point in the south wing.
等等
Wait.
其他人質怎麼辦
What about the other hostages?
你就放著他們不管了嗎
You're just going to leave them?
我得救你出去
Look, I need to get you to safety.
我不明白  我有什麼特殊的
I don't understand! What is so special about me?
怎麼回事
What's going on?
她不願意走
She won't leave.
我瞭解海倫娜
I know Helena.
她會把他們都殺了的
She's going to kill all of those people,
那些無辜的人
innocent people.
是你讓我展現自己的堅強
You wanted me to show you I'm strong.
我現在就給你看  我要留下來
This is me being strong. I'm staying.
你到底要不要幫我
Are you going to help me or not?
快把她帶出來
Get her out of there now!
我又不能直接把她打暈
It's not like I can just knock her out.
我不想你和海倫娜交鋒
I don't want you engaging Helena.
怎麼  你是怕她會做什麼嗎
What, you're afraid of what she'll do...
還是我會做什麼事
or what I'll do?
莎拉  你不是個殺手
Sara...you're not a killer.
我該是什麼就是什麼
I am what I need to be.
莎拉  你能聽到嗎
Sara, did you hear me?
我聽得到
I heard you.
亨德里克不在
Hendrik's not here.
有人想跟你打個招呼
There's someone I'd like you to say hello to.
什麼都別給他  莎拉
Don't give him anything, Sara.
奧利
Ollie!
最後一次機會
One last chance.
奧利弗換亨德里克
Oliver for Hendrik.
我說過了  亨德里克沒有
I told you! Look, Hendrik, he didn't make it
活著到島上  他淹死了
to the island, he drowned.
想想一年前  你不過是個大學女孩
To think it was only a year ago, you were a little college girl,
繞著男生轉
fretting about boys.
你什麼意思
What's your point?
你可不會騙人
You're not a good liar.
斯萊德  求你  住手
Slade! Stop, please!
他是你的朋友
Look, he's your friend!
剛剛就是電流穿過我朋友的聲音
That is the sound of electricity surging through my friend.
準確來說是5毫安培
Five milliamps, to be exact.
7毫安培能使心臟停跳
Seven causes cardiac arrest.
奧利弗剛才在6毫安培的時候暈過去了
Oliver just passed out with six milliamps.
一小時後如果亨德里克沒被帶到我面前
He'll be delivered with the fatal blow of seven
我就用7毫安培送他上路
in one hour if hendrik is not standing here by my side!
我死也不會回去的
There's no way in hell I'm going back there.
我有次差點結婚了
I was almost married once.
已經過了一小時了
It's been an hour,
我可是說話算話的
and I'm a woman of my word.
不信問我爸爸
Just ask my father.
會沒事的
Everything's going to be ok.
小心後面
Behind you!
奧利弗真的很喜歡讓他的女朋友變裝
Oliver sure does like to dress up his girls.
你還好嗎
You all right?
勞蕾爾她還在那
Laurel! She's still in there.
很高興再次見到你  勞蕾爾
Nice to see you again, Laurel.
海倫娜  聽我說
Helena, listen to me.
-這一切必須結束  -我同意
- This has to end. - I agree.
我父親被裝進棺材就結束
And it ends with my father in a box.
員警不會把你父親交出來的
The police are never going to hand over your father!
是的  他們不會
No, they won't.
所以要由你把他交給我
That's why you're going to do it.
很簡單
Simple trade--
用我父親來交換勞蕾爾
my father for Laurel.
威登酒吧
夥計們
Hey, guys?
我們還需要一些伏特加
We need more vodka.
好吧
Ok...
我自己去拿
I'll get it myself.
你們要帶我去哪兒
Where are you taking me?
安全屋
Safe house.
聽著  正門被記者的圍攻了
Listen, front's mobbed with reporters.
把波提納爾從後門帶出去
Let's take Bertinelli out the back.
把車開過來
Bring the van around.
好吧
Ow! All right.
-怎麼回事  -別怕
- Whoa! What the hell? - Don't worry about it.
-到底怎麼回事  -快上車
- What's going on? - Just get in the van!
特警隊已經做好準備闖進法院
SWAT's getting ready to breach the courthouse.
那我們現在就去換人
Then we make the trade now.
聽著  我可不會因為弗蘭克死了而失眠
Listen, I'm not going to lose any sleep over Frank.
你要把他交給他女兒嗎
But are you really going to serve him up to his daughter?
不
No.
今晚誰也不會死
No one dies tonight.
你還好嗎
Are you ok?
會沒事的
Everything's going to be fine.
我說過  不許講話
I said...no talking.
我們那天晚上談過
We talked that night.
你  奧利弗  湯米和我
You, Oliver, Tommy, and I.
吃晚飯的時候
At dinner.
我記得你說你的未婚夫被殺了
I remember you telling me your fiance was killed.
真的很遺憾
I'm so sorry.
你這麼說我們就是好朋友了嗎
Does this make us girlfriends?
不
No.
但是我明白失去一個人的滋味
But I know what it's like to lose someone.
可憐的勞蕾爾
Poor Laurel.
湯米把你甩了嗎
Did Tommy dump you?
沒有
No.
他死了
He died.
我始終放不下這件事
And I couldn't deal with it.
所以我開始酗酒
So I became a drunk.
每當遇到問題
Every problem I had,
我就用藥片或者酒精來解決
I solved with a pill or a drink.
我的朋友和家人們都試圖幫我
My friends and my family,
但我據他們千里之外
they tried to help me, but I wouldn't let them.
你不必這麼做的  海倫娜
You don't have to do this, Helena.
現在還不算太晚
It's not too late.
我需要這麼做
Yes, I do.
一旦黑暗駐進了你的內心
Because once you let the darkness inside,
它就永遠不會出去了
it never comes out.
海倫娜  你父親在我這
Helena. I have your father.
我需要一個四人小組  鑽石陣型
I want four men teams, diamond formations.
快速移動  精確狙擊
Move fast, shoot sharp.
還有一件事  治安維持者不是法律
One more thing-- vigilantes are not the law.
如果他們帶著面具出現  就給他們一槍
If they're wearing a mask, they get a bullet.
開始行動
Let's move out.
波提納爾立刻把手舉起來
Hands up, bertinelli! Do it now!
求求你別殺我  求求你
Please don't kill me! Please!
她告訴我
She--she told me--
如果我不穿上它  她就殺了我
She told me to wear it or she'd kill me!
她在哪
Where the hell is she?!
別那麼害怕  勞蕾爾  你或許能活下來呢
Don't look so scared, Laurel. You might just live through this.
你們要把我交到我女兒手裡嗎
So you're just going to hand me over to my daughter?
我還以為你們是好人
I thought you were the good guys!
閉嘴
Shut up.
還記得我說過關於克制的事嗎
Remember all that stuff I said about restraint?
忘了吧
Forget about it.
你不能通過變成海倫娜那樣的人來阻止她
You can't stop someone like Helena by becoming her.
怎樣能保護我愛的人  我就怎樣做
I'll do what I have to to protect someone I love.
亨德里克  拜託  把槍放下
Hendrik, please, put the gun down!
為什麼  那樣你就可以把我送回那個地獄去了嗎
Why? So you can send me back to that hell hole?
我可不這樣想
I don't think so!
我們任何人都不能決定我們之中誰活誰死
It's not for any of us to decide who lives and dies.
但亨德里克這種情況  我願意破例一次
But in Hendrik's case, I'd be willing to make an exception.
我要離開這  別阻止我
I'm leaving. Don't stop me.
說得倒好  你是不會開槍殺我的
Good at talking, but you will not kill me.
那你就試試
Let's find out.
長官  我們收到蘭斯女士手機的信號了
Sir, we've got a ping off Ms. Lance's cell phone.
她一定帶著電話
She must still have it on her.
在哪裡
Where?
在蓋爾街和西蒙街交匯的一個機械商店裡
A machine shop at Gail street and Simone.
需要我們趕過去嗎
Should we rally up there?
不需要  留守在你們的位置
Negative. Hold your location.
是的  長官
Yes, sir.
警官  在這裡好好鎮守
Sergeant, keep this position.
對你來說真諷刺啊  爸爸
Well, this is irony for you, dad.
吉米•戴戈斯諾的屍體
Didn't you have Jimmy D'agostino's body
就被你埋在隔壁的地下吧
buried under the building next door?
抱歉  女兒
I'm sorry, my girl.
現在你就要死了  我肯定你的確抱歉
Now you're about to die, I'm sure you are.
不
No.
我是對那個我曾經帶著去芭蕾課的小女孩抱歉
I'm sorry for that little girl i used to take to ballet class.
一起去滑雪旅行的小女孩
Go on ski trips with.
我曾幫著做數學作業的小女孩
The one I used to help with her math homework.
她討厭數學
Oh, she hated math.
抱歉我為她帶來了這麼多傷害
Sorry that I caused her so much hurt,
而她帶給我如此多的歡樂
'cause she brought me so much joy.
海倫娜
Helena!
不要殺他
Don't kill him.
那樣你就再也回不去了
You can never come back from that.
太晚了
It's too late.
我已經回不去了
I'm already gone.
再見  爸爸
Bye, dad.
可惡的治安維持者
Damn vigilantes!
你們觸犯了法律
You went above the law!
上次出現這種情況時  我把你從窗戶扔了出去
Last time this happened, I threw you out a window.
我當時有所保留呢
I was holding back.
但是這次不會了
I won't do that again.
不
No!
你不是殺人犯
You're not a killer.
你根本不知道真正的我是什麼樣子  勞蕾爾
You don't know who I am, Laurel, not really.
那就展現給我看
Then show me.
不
No...
應該是我的
It was supposed to be me.
應該是我來動手的
It was supposed to me who did it.
行了  波提納爾  夠了
All right, Bertinelli, that's enough.
快走
Go.
你怎麼進來的
How did you get in here?
我們家族為員警的退休基本捐了一大筆錢
My family makes a generous donation to the policemen's retirement fund.
所以我偶爾會讓他們幫個小忙
And every once in a while, I get to call in a favor.
那你應該讓他們把我
Hmm. Maybe you could ask them to send me
送去熱帶的監獄
to prison somewhere tropical.
我以為我的感覺會有所不同
You know, I thought I'd feel different.
但他死後  我的感覺沒變
Now that he's dead, but I don't.
你一直跟我說
And you always told me that...
殺了他也無濟於事
killing him wouldn't change anything.
你說得對
You were right.
但是我也有錯
But I was wrong, too.
什麼錯了
About what?
我以為我能幫你
I thought I could help you.
能阻止你殺人
Stop you from being a killer,
但是
but...
我才剛剛開始
I was just starting.
我以前也是個殺人犯
And I was a killer, too.
那現在呢
And what are you now?
我在努力變好
I'm trying to be better.
雖然很蠢  但是
It's so stupid, but...
我一直在想  既然他死了
I keep thinking, now that he's dead,
我父親和邁克爾在一起了  而我...
my father and Michael are together, and...
我仍然在這裡
I'm still here.
孤身一人
Alone.
你不是孤身一人
You're not alone.
你在對我做什麼
What are you doing to me?
羅馬時期
In Roman times,
罪犯會被做上標記
a criminal was branded
以讓世人分辨出他的罪行
to identify his crimes to the world
也永遠提醒他自己的所作所為
and to forever remind him of what he'd done.
莎朵的背上就有這個紋身
Shado wore this tattoo on her back.
你的餘生就一直背負著這個紋身吧
Now you shall wear it for the rest of your life,
不論你的生命有多麼短暫
however short that may be.
弗林
Flynn.
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
希望你做出了正確的選擇
I hope you've made the right choice.
是的
Yes.
我代表整個地檢辦辦公室
Look, on behalf of the entire DA's office,
向你道歉
I have to apologize.
亞當•唐納已經不在這裡工作了
Adam Donner's employment here has been terminated.
我們之前真的不知道他有什麼陰謀詭計
Obviously we had no idea what he was plotting.
但願如此
I would hope not.
很不幸  亞當沒有權利
Unfortunately, Adam was not authorized
讓你回來工作
to offer you your job back.
抱歉
I'm sorry,
但是一切都沒變
but nothing has changed.
不  變了
Yes, it has.
你說什麼
Excuse me?
你要把工作還給我  凱特
You are going to rehire me, Kate.
除非你想去向媒體解釋
Unless you feel like explaining to the press
自己手下的區助理檢察官
that your own assistant district attorney
就是今晚人質危機事件的幕後黑手
was the brilliant mastermind behind tonight's hostage crisis.
歡迎回來
Welcome back.
不得不說  真讓我刮目相看啊
I have to say, I am impressed.
我還以為你不會用威脅這麼骯臟的手段
I would have thought blackmail was a little dark for you.
最近有人告訴我
Someone recently told me,
一旦讓黑暗駐進自己的內心
once you let the darkness inside,
它就永遠不會出去了
it never comes out.
威登酒吧
你還在這裡幹什麼
What are you still doing up here?
思考
Thinking.
哭泣
Crying.
我和羅伊...
Roy and I are...
怎麼回事
What happened?
我抓到他跟一個賤人一起
I caught him with some slut.
就在那邊
Right over there, actually.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
他那樣做是為了把我推開
He was doing it to push me away,
這下起作用了
which clearly worked.
我  我不知道為什麼
I just... I don't know why.
為什麼大家說實話
Why is it so hard for everyone
就那麼難呢
just to tell the truth?
羅伊根本就不跟我說實話
I mean, Roy can't even tell me the truth
不告訴我到底為什麼跟我分手
of why he wants to end things with me.
媽媽  她...
Mom, she...
她守著那麼多秘密
She keeps all of these secrets.
難道你...
I mean, doesn't it...
你不覺得她還有什麼瞞著我們嗎
Doesn't it feel like she's still keeping something from us?
我也不知道  西婭
I don't know, Thea.
你是唯一一個不撒謊騙我的  奧利
You're the only one that doesn't lie to me, Ollie.
你是我認識的人中
You're the only one I know
唯一一個不瞞著我的
who doesn't keep secrets from me.
我先走了
Just, I got to go.
我開車送你吧
Let me drive you.
不用了  我現在想一個人靜一靜
No, I just want to be alone right now.
她沒事吧
Is she OK?
會沒事的
She will be.
最終會的
Eventually.
你今晚做得很棒
You did good tonight.
英雄都會那樣做的  對嗎
That's what heroes do, right?
這是個危險的城市
It's a dangerous city.
你不該一個人在街上的
You shouldn't be out in the streets alone.
威爾遜先生
Mr. Wilson?
叫我斯萊德就行
Please. Call me Slade.